

Nipesh Patel

Birth date: 15/07/1989

Address: H-102/ Krishna Empire, Near Yogi Nagar Township, Chhani,

Vadodara 391740.

Hello: - +91 9913174505 / +91 7574819499

Email: patelnipesh1989@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nipesh-patel-6b18753a

Summary

Customer service focused Technical Support Specialist with 7+ year's career experience in Products & Application support environment + Cloud + Python and shell scripting. Highly adept in systems analysis diagnostics and troubleshooting and conflict resolution. Exhibits excellent organizational and problem-solving skills. Works well in team environments and displays strong work ethic. Skilled problem-solver able to communicate with users at all levels of technical proficiency. Dedicated to Root cause Analysis.

Skill Highlights

- AWS
- EC2
- S3
- CloudWatch
- Redshift
- ALB
- VPC
- Security Groups
- Dynamo DB
- IAM
- AMI
- Route53
- SNS
- Linux
- API
- LDAP
- Python
- SSO

- Microsoft SQL server
- Retail J
- PcConnect anywhere
- SAP
- FTP
- E-POS
- VMware
- IIS
- Microsoft BizTalk
- Tomcat
- Networking
- Leadership
- Management
- Jenkins
- Docker
- sales force
- Shell Scripting
- SAP

Education

- Master of Science (MS) in Computer Networking, University of Bedfordshire, Luton, United Kingdom, July 2013.
- Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA), NPCCSM College, Kadi, HNGU University, 2010.

Certification:

- ITIL foundation 2011 edition, Axelos
- AWS Cloud Practitioner, Udemy
- AWS certified solutions architect associate, Udemy

Experience

InfoDesk India Pvt Ltd.

Product Support Specialist-Lead

Jan 2021 - Present

- Providing technical solutions to the clients globally on own products
- Troubleshooting feed RSS URL issues and providing solutions to the clients
- Monitoring tickets queue and own responsibility of all open tickets in the queue.
- Working on ticking tools like salesforce and JIRA
- working with IT infrastructure team, QA and Dev team when it is required.
- Working on Pgsql database currently.
- Identify the root cause and work accordingly.
- Identifying bug and reporting to the respective team and discussing with the management.
- Own responsibility of escalated or urgent issues including what to respond to the clients.
- Making documentation for knowledge sharing purpose.
- Conducting knowledge sharing KT session with the team.
- Initiate new ideas to improve existing or new process.
- Working within SLA.
- Providing assistance anytime that whatever team is required.
- Working on various technologies/tools like LDAP, Database, etc.
- Working on AWS on S3, EC2, ALB, Cloudwatch, DynamoDB and API.
- Troubleshooting through logs on Linux servers and front-end applications also.
- I have ability to adapt quickly and keep on improving the process.
- Involved in onboarding new clients/projects.
- Handling team's PPP individually each quarter and end of year
- Reporting to Global manager on daily basis.

InfoDesk India Pvt Ltd.

Support Specialist

Jan 2019 - Jan 2021

- Provide technical support to the global clients on own products.
- working with Infrastructure team if any issue related infrastructure.
- Leading and mentoring team. In addition, training newcomers to the business and team.
- explored more on linux servers and cloud like AWS as working on JAVA environment using web server as tomcat.
- Working towards root cause analysis.
- involved in deployment/system maintenance to execute.
- managing the team in terms of resources, assistance, rota management, policies, documentation, process improvement, minimizing escalation, knowledge transfer , more product learning and introducing new exercise to help individuals.

- rectify and resolve any infrastructure or server health related issue.
- coordinate with QA, devOps, sales team, higher management and development whenever it is required. In addition, using email method to communicate with clients.
- I am responsible to review all tickets where team need to respond to the client.
- working on some reporting over salesforce cloud which is being used as ticketing tool as well.
- Hands on psql, HTML, XML, Linux, AWS, JBOSS.

Paul Mason Consulting Pvt Ltd.

Application L2 Analyst

Sept 2018- Jan 2019

- Provide 2nd level support to all incidents related to Retail Java published by Oracle.
- Provides all level 2 support to UK/USA based clients remotely that all includes JAVA environment,
 EPOS system, servlet, Web application, database issues, data processing, etc.
- Serving customers through Retail Java based application.
- Working in ITIL environment.
- Responsible to provide level 2 support and other projects on demand.
- Involved in global issue and work accordingly.
- Coordinate with L3 when problem arises.
- Logging and investigate on incidents through ticketing system
- Coordinating with various functions from 1st level to hardware supplier.
- Responsible to handle incident queue management.
- Resolves any priority incidents.
- Working towards root cause analysis.
- Deployment, releases, User Support, Resolving Issues and Reporting.
- Building EPOS system through Oracle solutions.
- Hands on Mssql and Oracle.
- Using web server like Tomcat, Web sphere, IIS.
- Providing remote support through different ticket systems like Juniper, LANdesk, Kasaya, VNC,
 Zandesk, JIRA, Salesforce, IMS.
- Technical expertise on HTML and XMI files.

Paul Mason Consulting Pvt Ltd.

L2 operations Support Analyst

Jan 2016 - Aug 2018

- Provide 2nd level support to all incidents related to Epos system.
- Manage and monitor all installed systems and infrastructure
- Install, configure, test and maintain operating systems, application software and system management tools
- Proactively ensure the highest levels of systems and infrastructure availability
- Monitor and test application performance for potential bottlenecks, identify possible solutions, and work with developers to implement those fixes
- Maintain backup and redundancy strategies
- uses scripts or logs to increase system efficiency and lower the human intervention time on any tasks
- Coordinate with L3 and problem management to work on problem incidents.

- Working towards root cause analysis.
- Deployment, releases, User Support, Resolving Issues and Reporting.

Paul Mason Consulting Pvt Ltd.

May 2014 - Dec 2015

Level 1 Operations support Analyst

- I am supporting for global technology, tools, and operations processes.
- This is a technical position that requires identifying, troubleshooting, and resolving internal system
 problems as well as external customer-related IT issues. The role is a blend of general technical
 and business.
- Currently I am working on UK based clients provides tech support using SAP, Troubleshooting and other tools
- Currently, I am working on SQL server and RDP as well to work on client side systems.
- This role is part of a highly specialized support organization that is responsible for the daily operations of multiple industry leading trading exchanges and clearing systems. This is a customerfacing position
- I do support of the post-trade electronic systems. This is a customer-facing position that requires identifying, troubleshooting, and resolving internal system problems as well as external customer-related IT issues. The role is a blend of general technical.
- All work frames have critical platform where I do work.
- Working proactively to identify issues and resolving as initial authorized level.
- Coordinate with Level 2 team if support required.